A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Laurice Wassef FA516
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Laurice Wassef
1998-2002
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA516
3.6 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Conditions Governing Access note
Retrieval Requests:
All requests to view this collection are to be made by Box Number. Retrieval of individual folders is not permitted.
Ford Foundation
- DD Role and Responsibility -- Regular Meetings, 1998 (Box 1 (43786))
- Program Leadership Meeting, 1998 (Box 1 (43786))
- Leadership Retreat -- Regular Meetings, 1999 (Box 1 (43786))
- Cairo Planning Agendas, 2000 (Box 1 (43786))
- Program Budget Review FY 2000 -- Management Budget, 1999 (Box 1 (43786))
- Guidelines -- Learning Enhancement Funds, 2000-2001 (Box 1 (43786))
- Committee on Indigenous Peoples, 2000 (Box 1 (43786))
- American Indian Research and Grants Assessment Project Final Draft Report, Jul 2001 (Box 1 (43786))
- Leadership Meeting -- Regular Meetings, Mar 2001 (Box 1 (43786))
- Leadership Retreat -- Regular Meetings, Jun 2001 (Box 1 (43786))
- Leadership Retreat -- Regular Meetings, Sep 2001 (Box 1 (43786))
- Leadership Retreat -- Regular Meetings, Dec 2001 (Box 1 (43786))
- OVP Team Meeting -- All Assets OVP and OVP Grants Admin Staff, 2001 (Box 1 (43786))
- Laufer Green Isaac -- Background, 2001 (Box 1 (43786))
- LEF Project -- Asset Building Breakthroughs, 1997-2000 (Box 1 (43786))
- Laufer Green Isaac -- Brochures, 2001 (Box 1 (43786))
- Laufer Green Isaac -- Strategy, 2001 (Box 1 (43786))
- Learning Enhancement FAP, Feb 2000 (Box 1 (43786))
- University of Michigan, Feb 2000 (Box 1 (43786))
- LGI Committee Handbook, 2002-2003 (Box 1 (43786))
- Laufer Green Isaac -- Spanish translation, [2002] (Box 1 (43786))
- Laufer Green Isaac -- Vietnamese Translation, 2002 (Box 1 (43786))
- LEF -- Laufer Green Isaac -- Positioning Piece, 2003 (Box 1 (43786))
- Program Leadership, Mar 2003 (Box 1 (43786))
- Learning Presentations 1999 (Box 2 (43787))
- About Learning Presentation, 1999 (Box 2 (43787))
- Communications Plan -- Learning Agenda, [2000] (Box 2 (43787))
- Assets Program Forum, Sep 14, 2000 (Box 2 (43787))
- Learning Program Updates, Jun 2000 (Box 2 (43787))
- Asset Building and Community Development Seminar, 2000 (Box 2 (43787))
- Learning Tools, 1999-2000 (Box 2 (43787))
- ASSETS Learning Publications Inventory, [2002] (Box 2 (43787))
- Learning Tools -- RCD Chart, 1996-1998 (Box 2 (43787))
- Learning Tools -- Senior Director Ideas, 1999 (Box 2 (43787))
- Learning/Practice Methodologies Soc Behavior Change, 2000 (Box 2 (43787))
- Learning Systems -- PSJ, 2000 (Box 2 (43787))
- Kahane -- Private Sector Inventory Learning Projects, 2001 (Box 2 (43787))
- Kahane -- Corporate Involvement Initiative, 2001-2002 (Box 2 (43787))
- Private Sector -- Markets, 2002 (Box 2 (43787))
- Barry -- Community Based Forestry, 2000 (Box 2 (43787))
- Barry -- Lessons from Hurricane Mitch, 2002 (Box 2 (43787))
- Davie -- Black Churck Assessment Project, 1999-2000 (Box 2 (43787))
- Lopez -- E&D Centers of Excellence Extranet, 2001 (Box 2 (43787))
- Mallee -- Natural Resource Degradation and Population Growth, 2000 (Box 2 (43787))
- Mallee -- Ford Foundation Work with Forestry Departments of Yunnan and Sichuan Provinces SW, 2002 (Box 2 (43787))
- Menzies -- K-Rep, 2001 (Box 2 (43787))
- Pearson -- Ford Foundation Grants to Support New and Emerging Foundations, 2001 (Box 2 (43787))
- Pradhan -- Water Systems as Community Assets in India, 2002 (Box 2 (43787))
- Rizvi -- Fifty Years -- Ford Foundation Work in India, 2001 (Box 2 (43787))
- Winters -- Expanding Ford Foundation's Response to AIDS, 2000 (Box 2 (43787))
- Program Officers Working with Community Foundations Meeting, 1996-1997 (Box 3 (43788))
- Affinity Learning Group -- Indigenous Peoples, 2000 (Box 3 (43788))
- Committee on Indigenous Peoples (CIP) Project, 2000 (Box 3 (43788))
- Affinity Group on Development Finance (AGDF) -- General, 1997-1999 (Box 3 (43788))
- Affinity Group on Development Finance (AGDF) -- Meeting Memos/Miscellaneous, 1999 (Box 3 (43788))
- Affinity Group on Development Finance (AGDF) -- Schedule, 1999 (Box 3 (43788))
- Affinity Group on Development Finance (AGDF) -- Operating Plan/Status 1, 1999 (Box 3 (43788))
- Affinity Group on Development Finance (AGDF) -- Workplans FY 2001, 1999-2000 (Box 3 (43788))
- Environment and Development Affinity Group (EDAG) -- Annual Meeting -- Tucson, 1998 (Box 3 (43788))
- Environment and Development Affinity Group (EDAG) -- Meeting (Zimbabwe-Mozambique), 1999-2000 (Box 3 (43788))
- Environment and Development Affinity Group (EDAG) -- Meeting Notes/Workplan, 2000-2001 (Box 3 (43788))
- Environment and Development Affinity Group (EDAG) -- 2002 Annual Meeting, 2001-2001 (Box 3 (43788))
- Reproductive Health Affinity Group (RHAG) -- Workplan, 1998-2000 (Box 3 (43788))
- Reproductive Health Affinity Group (RHAG) -- Meeting -- Bahia, Brazil, Oct 1999 (Box 3 (43788))
- Natural Resources Affinity Group (NRAG), 1996 (Box 3 (43788))
- Natural Resources Affinity Group (NRAG) -- Istanbul, 1997 (Box 3 (43788))
- Natural Resources Affinity Group (NRAG), 1997 (Box 3 (43788))
- Natural Resources Affinity Group (NRAG), 1998 (Box 3 (43788))